Amen.
No, no.
No, no!
No, no, no!
No!
Aiuto!
No, no, no!
No!
Aiuto!
- I'm sorry, but how much
longer will this take?
I've got to take
my vows tonight,
and I really can't be late.
Do you speak English?
- Sorry for the wait.
It's extra work now
when someone arrives
without a return ticket.
Parli italiano?
I ask if
you're learning Italian.
- Oh, I'm trying, but it's
a lot harder than I thought.
- Mm.
So this convent,
they bought you the ticket?
- Mm-hmm.
- You're very young to
be a nun, aren't you?
- It's a different life, yeah?
It must have been
a hard decision.
- I don't think
of it like that,
as a decision.
- Very well.
I hope you find what you're
looking for, Sister Cecilia.
- Thank you.
- Reverend Mother.
- I'm sorry.
- She says you're pretty.
- Grazie.
I'm Sister Cecilia.
- Isabelle.
- Let me show you
to your room.
Our Lady of Sorrows
was founded in 1632
as a refuge for elder sisters
before their transition
to heaven.
- It's really beautiful.
- Yes, it is.
Buongiorno, sorelle.
And we work hard
to keep it that way.
Our sister's final
days should be
a pleasing environment
to help distract from all
the sickness and suffering.
All of this, it was built on
the catacomb of St. Stephen.
- Catacombs?
- It's off limits.
- Ciao.
- The one in the wheelchair,
her tumor has metastasized.
So we expect her to meet God
by the end of the week.
- You talk about it
so casually.
- Death is a part
of everyday life here.
It's best to just play along
with their delusions
unless they get violent.
Be careful of this one.
She bites.
- I'm sorry.
- Living quarters
for the caretakers
are down there and upstairs.
Morning prayer begins
at 5:00 a.m.,
communal meal is after.
And if you have any
dietary restrictions,
we cannot accommodate them.
And this room is yours.
- Thank you, Sister.
I feel honored
to serve alongside you.
- You're very sweet.
- Thank you.
- I don't mean that
as a compliment.
I'm sure this must
feel very romantic,
but this is our life.
And I promise you,
work is hard,
physically and emotionally.
So if you're here
to find yourself,
there are easier ways.
- I'm not.
- Tonight, you do not
have to take your vows.
You can still go back,
and God will forgive you.
- I think he has
sufficiently prepared me.
- The ceremony will start
at 1700 in the chapel.
Don't be late.
- Oh, ciao.
- Ciao.
I'm sorry.
- No, it's fine.
- I'm Cecilia.
- Oh, I'm Guendalina.
You can call me Gwen.
My room is there.
Where in the States
are you from?
- Just outside
of Detroit, Michigan.
- Mm-hmm.
- Are you
from around here or...
- Closer to Milan.
You're far from home.
- Yeah, my parish closed.
- Did the priest
get in trouble?
- No.
No, no, no, no, no, no,
nothing, nothing like that.
Just low attendance.
And that church was
my family, my home.
Leaving, I felt pretty lost.
But then Father Tedeschi,
he reached out to me.
- Yeah.
He has a talent.
Sniffing out broken birds.
Oh, I didn't want
to offend you.
I think that maybe we are all
head cases or runaways.
- Which one are you?
- Both.
Next time if you want,
you can lock the door.
- Thanks.
- Sister Cecilia.
- Father Tedeschi, it's nice
to meet you in person.
- We all feel so blessed
to have you here.
How's the Italian
coming along?
- Comme ci, comme ci.
It's fine.
I will translate for you.
- Let us rejoice, for the
marriage of the Lamb has come,
and his brides have
made themselves ready.
- Sorella Cecilia.
- Sister Cecilia.
- Do you promise
to follow Christ
more closely
by living a life devoid
of material possessions?
Do you promise to free
yourself from the demands
of a human relationship
and follow with joy
when he shall come again--
a vow of poverty,
chastity, and obedience?
- I do.
- May God give you the
strength to fulfill your vows
faithfully and joyfully.
May you shine his light
for the world to see.
- How are you feeling?
Full.
- Yeah, we don't--
we don't really have anything
like this back home.
- Cecilia, this is your home.
I know, I know.
I felt the same way
when I started here.
I didn't grow up
wanting to be a priest.
My first career was
in sciences, biology.
I was almost two decades in,
and I couldn't
understand the world
any better than back
when I was in Sunday school.
And then God showed me a path.
He brought me here.
This is where I
was meant to be.
I'm sorry.
I'm so sorry.
Two glasses in and I can't
stop talking about myself.
I'm so sorry.
- No, it's OK.
It's OK.
- What about you?
I imagine it was
a difficult decision.
- I mean, yes,
it seemed so far away.
But the opportunities
back in the States,
I didn't feel like
that's what God saved me for.
- If it's too personal--
- No.
When I was 12 years old,
there was this part
of the Saginaw River
that would always freeze over.
And no matter how
cold it was, I would
always walk out onto the ice.
And I would do this thing
where I took my gloves off,
and I would place my hands
right on the ice.
And I would hold
them there until I
couldn't feel anything.
I don't remember
the ice breaking.
I just, I remember
this sharp pain of cold.
The paramedics,
they tried to revive me,
but my heart stopped
for almost seven minutes.
- That sounds terrifying.
- I know God saved
me for a reason, but...
I guess I'm still searching
for what that reason is.
Now will you--
will you excuse me, please?
- Ciao?
- Are you OK?
I'll go get some help.
Cecilia.
- Reverend Mother,
I'm so sorry.
I heard her crying and--
- It's OK.
You have a question.
All right.
- What is this place?
- Suffered?
This is the--
- Yes.
We suffer.
Suffering is love.
- In the name of the Father
and the Son
and the Holy Spirit.
Amen.
Bless me, Father,
for I have sinned.
It's been three days
since my last confession.
I was--
I was careless last night.
I must have drank too much
wine and embarrassed myself
in front of Mother Superior.
I promise to carry myself with
grace because I want nothing
more than to belong here.
I'm afraid I've already
messed things up.
I'm sorry for these...
Yearnments.
Hello?
- What did she say?
- God is good.
God is great.
- God, my head hurts.
- Too much blood of Christ?
- No.
- What a blessing
to mentor you both.
Finish eating.
We have work to do.
- What does that mean?
- Oh, nothing.
I really like her.
I'm super excited.
- Clean their back thoroughly.
And if the consistency
of their feces seems off,
you let Dr. Gallo know.
- Ciao.
all: Ciao.
- We want to hang the larger
items towards the front
and the shorter items
towards the back.
That way, the wind can
blow underneath it.
- I'm sorry.
I can't.
In the name of the Father and
the Son and the Holy Spirit.
Amen.
- Sister, let's--
let's get you to bed.
- Buonanotte, Sister.
- It could have been worse.
She could have
given you bangs.
- Gwen, I'm not joking.
She had scars
on the bottom of her feet.
- It's not what you thought
it would be, huh, this place?
- No, it's
definitely different.
- It's better than where
I came from, though.
- What do you mean?
- There is a boy.
There was a boy, I mean.
- What happened with this boy?
- He hit me.
I hit him back.
Once I left him,
I went to those support
groups, you know?
There were these nuns there.
And I thought, these women
have a very good life.
They have a place
to live, a job
where they can keep
their clothes on,
nothing to worry about.
So I signed up.
- Wait, so you don't
even believe in God?
- Of course I do.
Life is so cruel.
Only a man can be responsible.
Oh, my God, I was joking.
Are you OK?
- I don't feel good.
- I'm going to call a doctor.
- Could you please tell
Cardinal Merola your vows?
- My vows?
- Your vows.
- I swore to three vows
when I got here,
of obedience,
poverty, and chastity.
- He's asking if you have--
- I understand.
I have.
I have been obedient,
your Eminence.
- Yes, I, I own nothing.
I want for nothing.
- I'm sorry,
why are you asking me this?
- It's OK.
Just answer the question,
if you would, Cecilia.
- Of course, I've been chaste,
your Eminence.
- Before you arrived, did you
have congress with a man?
- Congress with--no, no.
- Have you ever had
congress with a man?
- I've not broken my vows.
I've never been with
a man or a woman, nobody.
- You'll not be punished.
We just want to know
the truth.
- I'm not lying, Father.
- What is going on?
- What are they saying?
- No.
- What are you--
what are you looking at?
- One last time.
- Have you ever had
sexual intercourse?
- Why are you asking me this?
- You are with child.
- He believes you.
It's a miracle.
- Out of all the women in the
world, why did he choose me?
- You told me
who saved your life,
who sent you on the path
that led you here.
Cecilia, you've been
searching for a reason.
God saved you.
This is it.
Blessed are the meek,
for they shall
inherit the Earth.
- No working.
Remember,
your only job is baby.
- How long before they
start calling you Mary?
- Isabelle! Isabelle!
- No!
- No, no!
- Heartbeat is stable.
There's no bleeding.
- Praise be.
- We'll run some blood tests
to check for distress.
But he appears to be OK.
- But I'm not OK.
Father, Isabelle said
it was supposed to be her.
Why would she say that?
- Well, Isabelle
has been losing
her battle with mental illness
for a while now.
And seeing you
and the miracle,
it clearly triggered
something,
whether it be jealousy--
- She tried to drown me.
- You're right.
You're right.
And I'll make sure
this never happens again.
- I want to see
another doctor.
- Why? Dr. Gallo--
- Takes care of old women.
I want to go to
a real hospital, please.
- He's a licensed
obstetrician.
- Thursday through Saturdays
I deliver babies at Cosentino.
- A hospital is not
what you need right now.
You're perfectly healthy.
- I just puked up
one of my teeth.
- Hospitals aren't
the safest of places.
We wouldn't want you
to get sick.
- Or for the word
to get out, you know.
The safest thing
is for you to stay
here until the Savior is born.
- Oh, Isabelle.
- Cecilia, you need
to stand up for yourself.
- Gwen, shh.
- Open your eyes.
I don't trust this place.
- I don't think
we can just leave.
- Cecilia, you're
five months pregnant,
and you haven't even
been to a hospital.
We can take care of this.
How can we trust
what's inside you?
- Maybe God is--
- God has nothing
to do with this.
- Sisters,
is something the matter?
I can see you--
Fuck this.
- Sorella--
No!
No! No!
- "For Satan himself
often masquerades
as an angel of light."
Gwen.
No!
No, no!
No.
- Shh.
Santa.
- Please help me.
We have to leave.
- You will never leave here.
- Something's wrong.
I don't want to die.
I don't.
Uh-huh.
- What are you--
what are you doing?
Go!
Go, go!
- Clean yourself.
Clean yourself.
- God will never forgive you.
- I want to apologize
if any of my actions
made you feel scared.
And I want to reassure you
that you're safe.
- What did you do to me?
- When you look at this,
what do you see?
Some people might
see just an old piece
of iron, a rusty nail.
For those of us who know,
we see proof
of Jesus' sacrifice,
a symbol of his suffering.
And for 2,000 years,
that's all it was.
But we looked closer,
and we found blood,
tissue,
little fragments of bone,
a genetic code.
All we had to do
was crack it--
the key to resurrection.
- You're insane.
- Let me show you.
It's taken us 20 years
of trial and error,
20 years for God to deliver
unto us the knowledge
and the perfect
fertile vessel.
- Is this what's inside me?
- No.
These are all our failures.
What's inside you
is our success.
I left the field of genetics
because some people
disagreed with the ethics
of my experiment.
So many people have such a
narrow view of its potential.
But here in the church,
here they
understood
that a simple procedure
could bring us salvation.
- You're playing God.
- I am not playing God.
Do you know what it's like
to watch the miracle die
in the womb, to fail God
again and again and again,
but find the strength
to keep going?
This is my calling.
And this, this is yours.
- No.
What are you doing?
What's--what's going on?
What is that?
What are you--
what are you doing?
Please stop.
Stop, stop, stop, stop.
Please, please, stop.
Stop!
- May you never stray again.
- No.
No, no!
Stop!
- Blessed are the meek--
- No, no, no.
Please no.
- For they shall inherit--
- No, no, no, no, please, no.
- The Earth.
- No, no!
No!
- Wait.
Wait.
- How long have you
been targeting me?
- Please, si confessi.
- Was it since the accident?
What's going to happen
when it's done?
You think it's gonna,
what, save the world?
End it?
That's what Revelation
says, right?
This is not God's work.
- Very well.
If this is not
the will of God,
why does God not stop us?
- Hm.
He's moving.
Ah.
- I'll be right back.
- You will save us.
God damn it.
- Oh, my God.
Cecilia, what have you done?
- Cecilia,
this won't solve anything.
If you die,
we'll find another.
You can end this.
All you need to do
is deliver our Savior.
No!
Cecilia.
Let go of me!
- In the name of the Father,
the Son, and the Holy Spirit.
Amen.
Hail Mary, full of grace,
the Lord is with thee.
Blessed art thou among
women, and blessed
is the fruit
of thy womb, Jesus.
Holy Mary...
- No, no!
- Mother of God,
pray for us sinners...
Now and at the hour--
- No.
Fuck you.
- ♪ Ave Maria ♪
♪ Grátia plena ♪
♪ Maria grátia plena ♪
♪ Ave, ave Dóminus ♪
♪ Dóminus tecum ♪
♪ Ave Maria ♪
♪ Grátia plena ♪
♪ Maria grátia plena ♪
♪ Ave, ave Dóminus ♪
♪ Dóminus tecum ♪
♪ Ave Maria ♪
♪ Grátia plena ♪
♪ Maria grátia plena ♪
♪ Ave, ave Dóminus ♪
♪ Dóminus tecum ♪
♪ Ave Maria ♪